# **DAVID YUCHEN WANG**

Email: davidw0311@gmail.com Mobile: +65 9192 3429 Website: davidw0311.github.io LinkedIn

As a master's student studying Computing and AI at the National University of Singapore, I have over 3 years of work experience in the deployment and research of generative AI models, reinforcement learning, computer vison, and deep learning. I am a quick learner, an excellent team player, and possess strong work ethic. I am fluent in English and Mandarin, currently hold a Canadian citizenship and am seeking opportunities starting June 2024.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **National University of Singapore**

Aug 2023 - Dec 2024 (expected)

Master of Computing - Specialization in Artificial Intelligence

Thesis: Event-based cameras for 3D computer vision - supervisor Dr. Lee Gim Hee

**Courses:** Probabilistic Graphical Models, Deep Learning, Distributed Systems, AI Decision making, 3D Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Big Data Systems

# University of British Columbia, Canada

Sep 2018 - May 2023

Bachelor of Applied Science - Major in Engineering Physics, Minor in Commerce.

• UBC Presidential Scholars Award Recipient, Dean's Honors List

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Edge AI Developer** 

Aug 2023 - Present

Pensees Singapore - https://www.pensees.sg

- Adapted state-of-the-art generative **diffusion pipelines** for iOS using SwiftUI and Bazel, leveraging enhancements with **CoreML, MPS**, and **Metal** to achieve native on-device functionality with platform-specific optimization.
- Spearheaded the project development, integrating insights from weekly analyses of cutting-edge **research papers** to enhance team expertise and guide project trajectory, built and launched an **Al-drawing app** within 2 months.
- Acquired and applied expertise in various cutting-edge methods for use and deployment of large-scale image diffusion models, including **controlNet**, **LoRAs**, **consistency models**, and **NLP prompting**.

# **Machine Learning Research Assistant**

May 2021 - Aug 2023

TRIUMF - Canada's Particle Accelerator Centre - https://www.triumf.ca

- Developed **Bayesian Optimization** model to optimize particle beamlines and boost speed by 2400% and accuracy by 120% compared to human operators.
- Designed efficient physics simulations for use on policy gradient reinforcement learning models. Integrated first Alcontrolled interface on particle accelerators.
- Published experimental findings as first author in paper *Accelerator Tuning with Deep Reinforcement Learning* and gave video and poster presentation at **NeurIPS 2021** workshop.

# **Machine Learning Engineer**

May 2022 - Sep 2022

Yakoa.io - Web3 Startup - https://www.yakoa.io

- Implemented **image segmentation** framework in PyTorch from research papers to detect fraudulent features in NFT images with high accuracy.
- Deployed **self-supervised classification** models on AWS instances and fine-tuned models on a dataset of 8 million images, improving model run-times by over 300%.
- Employed **statistical analysis** of latent space of self-supervised models. Optimized hyperparameters and visualized results using Weights & Biases, leading to 150% improvement in validation accuracy.

Al Research Intern Jan 2020 - May 2020

Huawei Technologies Canada - Vancouver Big Data Lab

- Enhanced data-preprocessing speeds for large image datasets by 300% through designing scripts in Python and Bash.
- Boosted team productivity by 500% through configuring **custom environments** in Docker to allow parallelization of model training through cloud GPU clusters.
- Fine-tuned **deep-learning** models for **image classification** and **object detection** in TensorFlow and PyTorch. Organized documentation and presented findings to team, leading to 120% improvements on model accuracy.

# **Captain and Navigation Sub-Team Lead**

Sep 2019 - May 2023

UBC AgroBot - Student Engineering Design Team - https://ubcagrobot.com

- Devised project roadmaps, established a 2-year budgeting timeline, and utilized **Agile methodology** to manage a team of 70 members across 6 sub-teams to bring robot to the 2023 METRICS ACRE international competition.
- Led a team of 8 members to integrate software with hardware systems onboard robot. Interfaced with camera, lidar, and gyro sensors and utilized **computer vision** and PID control to achieve **autonomous navigation** through crop fields.

#### **SKILLS**

Programing languages: Python, Java, Swift, MATLAB, C++, C, C#, Julia, R, HTML, CSS

Libraries: PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, OpenCV, Numpy, SciPy, Matplotlib, Weights & Biases Frameworks: Linux, Bash, Bazel, Xcode, Slurm, ROS, Gazebo, AWS, GIT, Docker, Conda, Arduino

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Accelerator Tuning with Deep Reinforcement Learning - <a href="https://ml4physicalsciences.github.io/2021/files/NeurIPS">https://ml4physicalsciences.github.io/2021/files/NeurIPS</a> ML4PS 2021 125.pdf

NeurIPS 2021 - Workshop for Machine Learning and the Physical Sciences

#### **PROJECTS**

# **Vector Quantized Variational Autoencoders for White Blood Cell Detection**

Sep 2021 - Apr 2022

NUS Deep Learning Project

- Designed a custom, novel deep learning architecture in PyTorch, by stacking vector quantized variational autoencoders, to allowing for self-supervised pretraining and few-shot learning on classification of white blood cells.
- Implemented custom data loaders, and trained model in Slurm clusters to achieve 98% testing accuracy, as well as 90% testing accuracy using a 1% subset of training data.

### **Distributed Multi-server Game Design**

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

NUS Distributed Systems project

- Designed and built distributed peer-to-peer maze game leveraging Java RMI, socket communication, and multi-threaded server logic capable of adapting to node failures while maintaining a consistent game state.
- Achieved 100% pass in extensive stress test, thoroughly validating system's scalability, crash-tolerance, and throughput.

# **Self-Driving and License Plate Detection**

Jun 2021 - Sep 2021

UBC ENPH 353 Project Course

- Utilized Robotic Operating System (**ROS**) with **computer vision** algorithms to steer an autonomous vehicle through a simulated world and avoid moving obstacles with 0% collision rate.
- Generated custom datasets and trained **deep neural network** models in TensorFlow Keras to identify license plates in a noisy environment and classify their characters with 90% accuracy.
- Led labs and tutorials as a **Teaching Assistant** in next year for a class of 3rd year students and provided guidance in course concepts, software architecture, and working within **Linux** environments.

# **Autonomous Recycling Robot**

Jul 2020 - Aug 2020

UBC ENPH 253 Project Course

- Designed and soldered custom PCBs to interface with an STM32 micro-controller, with consideration of power limits, current distribution, and noise isolation.
- Investigated PCBs using an oscilloscope and a multimeter to discover and fix 100% of circuit issues.
- Implemented **PID control** system in C++ using reflectance sensors and employed sonar to collect and deposit soda cans with 80% accuracy.

#### LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Captain - UBC AgroBot Design Team (Sep. 2022 - May 2023)

Grad Year Representative - UBC Engineering Students Council (Sep. 2022 - May 2023)

Teaching Assistant - UBC (2020 - 2023)

3rd year Machine Learning Project Course, 1st year Introductory Physics Course, 1st year Experimental Physics Course Student Orientation Program Leader - UBC (Jun. 2020 - Sep. 2020)

President of Environment Club - Dover Bay Secondary School (2015 - 2018)